没有放晴的迹象
No sign of it letting up.
只能迟到了
Just gonna have to be late.
老实说  我不急着离开这里
Frankly, I'm in no rush to leave this party --
多谢你父亲对威士忌
thanks to your father's excellent taste
和女儿的绝佳品味
in Scotch and daughters.
他懂行嘛
Oh, the man knows his stuff.
断电  拜托
Blackout. Come on.
肯定是风暴引起的
Must be from the storm.
等等  我知道我父亲在这儿
Hold on. I know my dad keeps
放了个手电筒
a flashlight here somewhere.
你听到了吗
Did you hear that?
有人企图闯进来吗
Is someone trying to break in?
终结即将到来
Finis omnium nunc est.
断电  电话不能用
So, the power is out, the phones are down.
知道这意味着什么吗
You know what that means?
不会有深夜工作电话
No late-night calls from work
打断我们的裸体扭扭乐游戏
to interrupt our game of naked Twister.
等等  你怎么还穿着衣服
What, why are you still dressed?
我得去趟分局
I've got to go to the precinct.
什么  现在吗
What? Now?!
没有什么比断电更浪漫了
T-There's nothing more romantic than a blackout.
是啊  也没有比这更致命的了
Yeah, and nothing more deadly.
你跟我一样清楚  一发生断电
You know as well as I do that as soon as the lights go out,
就会发生坏事
bad things happen.
那是什么
What the hell's that?
侦探社办公室的紧急信号
The panic signal from the P.I. Office.
阿丽克西斯独自在那边时我就会打开
I had it set up for when Alexis is there by herself.
没有信号
No service.
贝克特警监呼叫中心
This is Captain Beckett to Central.
阿丽克西斯
Alexis?
怎么回事  你没事吧
What happened? Are you all right?
嗯  那人拿着斧子闯了进来
Yeah. That guy broke in with an ax,
吼了一句拉丁文
yelling something in Latin.
然后倒地死掉了
Then he just dropped dead.
他说了什么
What did he say?
不知道  发生得太快了
I don't know. It all happened so fast.
他是拿那个闯进来的吗
Is that what he broke in with?
是啊  这才叫硬闯派对呢
Yep. Talk about crashing a party.
原来是楼下大堂的消防斧
Turns out it's the fire ax from the downstairs lobby.
那么闯入者肯定是上来的路上拿的
So our intruder must've grabbed it on his way up.
为什么啊  想闯进这间办公室
But why? I mean, there's easier ways
明明有更简单的办法
to break into this office.
是啊  而且更安静
Yeah, and more silent.
他绝对是没打算让人不备
He certainly wasn't planning on sneaking up on anyone.
你查到他身份了吗
You get an ID on the guy?
没有  没有钱包
No. No wallet, and your, uh,
而且你的便携指纹机器不好使了
portable fingerprint thingumajiggy is down
天气的原因
due to weather.
他左侧受伤  导致流血致死
He bled to death from a wound in his left side.
我猜  不管是什么刺伤了他
My guess is whatever he was stabbed with
刺穿了他的锁骨下动脉
punctured his subclavian artery.
之后  他大概坚持了30分钟
After that, he would've had about 30 minutes
最多一小时
to an hour, tops.
他晚上九点拿着这东西进来
Well, he came in here with this around 9:00 p.m.
之后很快就倒地了
He keeled over shortly thereafter.
那么他肯定是8点到8:30间受伤的
So he must've been stabbed between 8:00 and 8:30.
他戴了一条医院腕带
There's a -- There's a hospital bracelet.
闯入者名叫G·肖
Our intruder's name is G. Shaw,
他是
and he was a patient at...
皮科莫精神病院的病人
Peakmore Psychiatric Facility.
哎呦
Yikes.
你认识那里吗
You know it?
那是一家罪犯精神病院
It's a psychiatric hospital for the criminally insane.
这位挥斧疯子是个落跑精神病人
Our ax-wielding psycho is an escaped mental patient.
备用发电机不太好使
Back-up generator's not working so well.
是啊  按说这样的地方该很先进才对
Yeah, place like this you'd think would be state of the art.
我们是为一名逃跑犯人而来
We're here about an escaped inmate
他刚刚企图用斧子杀两个人
just tried to kill two people with an ax.
稍等
Wait here.
如果我住这里  肯定也会想跑
Yo, I'd try to escape, too, if I lived here.
谁知道他们都对病人做什么呢
Who knows what they're doing to them back there.
不可能比历史上发生过的事更糟了
Can't be anything worse than what we did historically.
很多文化都误将精神疾病当做妖术的征兆
Many cultures mistook mental illness for a sign of sorcery.
治疗从祈祷
Treatments ranged from, well, prayer
到颅骨钻孔释放恶魔都有
to drilling holes in the skull to release the demons.
绝对是治疗比
Definitely a case of the cure
疾病更糟的一个案例
being worse than the disease.
院长这就出来
The Director's coming out now.
多谢
Thanks, man.
警探们  我是布鲁克·马丁医生
Detectives, I'm Dr. Brock Martin.
你们找到加百列·肖了吗
Did you find Gabriel Shaw?
不  是他找到了我们
No, he found us,
但此前他被捅伤  伤势致命
but not before he was fatally stabbed.
太可怕了
That's terrible.
加百列·肖在皮科莫待了20年了
Gabriel Shaw's been here at Peakmore for the last 20 years.
他做了什么
What did he do?
他闯进了一个沃伦·克朗的家
He broke into the house of a man named Warren Crowne,
企图杀他和他全家
tried to kill him and his entire family.
那个大慈善家沃伦·克朗吗
Warren Crowne the philanthropist?
我记得当时的新闻标题
I remember the headlines.
他的袭击者不是自称复仇天使吗
Didn't his attacker say he was some kind of avenging angel?
大天使加百列  圣徒信使
The archangel Gabriel -- the divine messenger.
教义问答学得好
Catechism class.
加百列·肖深信
Gabriel Shaw was convinced
他在执行上帝的任务
that he was on a mission from God
要铲除世界的邪恶
to rid the world of evil.
即便经历了20年的抗精神病药和
It was a mission that even 20 years of antipsychotic drugs
电击疗法都无法让他放弃这个任务
and electroshock therapy could not dissuade him from.
知道谁可能会想他死吗
Any idea who might've wanted him dead?
没有
None.
加百列几乎与外面世界毫无联系
Gabriel's contact with the outside world was virtually nil.
他的房间就在这边
His room's down here.
知道他是怎么逃的吗
Any idea how he might've escaped?
知道  他偷了一位护工的钥匙卡
Yes, he, uh, he stole a keycard from one of our orderlies.
我们今天大概中午时候就发现他失踪了
Uh, we realized he was missing around noon today.
中午  你们之前为什么没报警
Noon? Why the hell didn't you call the police before?
我现在意识到我们是该报警
We should have. I realize that now.
他挥着斧子冲进了我的办公室
The man came to my office wielding an ax.
所以我派出了
Which is why I sent out
一组护工找加百列
a group of orderlies looking for Gabriel.
他们找了一整天  空手而归
They searched all day and came back empty-handed.
-只是  -只是什么
- Except - Except what?
有一位护工还没回来呢
One of the orderlies hasn't come back yet.
戴维·霍比
Uh, Dave Holmby.
我想打给他  但电话服务中断了
I-I-I tried calling him, but the phones are out.
戴维和加百列之前有什么过节吗
Have Dave and Gabriel had any problems in the past?
他们是有些矛盾
They've had... issues, yes.
事实上  加百列偷的就是戴维的钥匙卡
In fact, it was Dave's keycard that Gabriel stole.
但戴维在我们这儿干很久了
But Dave's been with us a long time.
他不是会杀人的人
He's not the type of person to kill anyone,
如果你们在这么想的话
if that's what you're thinking.
你们派护工去抓一个暴力
You sent an orderly out to recapture a violent,
精神不稳定的人
mentally unstable man.
他或许是想制服加百列
It's possible he was trying to subdue Gabriel
结果事态失控了
and things got out of control.
于是戴维捅伤了加百列
So, Dave stabs Gabriel,
但又在暴风雨中与他失散
but then loses him in the storm.
各位  你们听到了吗
Guys, are you hearing that?
那里面有什么东西
Something in here.
怎么不说你们有鼠患
Might've told me about your rodent problem.
我们没有
We don't have one.
一般没有
Not usually.
肯定是因为暴风雨跑上来了
Must've been driven to higher ground by the storm.
那是本《圣经》吗
That a bible?
是啊  但上面有画
Yeah, but with... drawings...
画的是恶魔  通篇都是
of demons, page after page of them.
莱恩  哈维  有人吗
Ryan, Javi, anyone there?
收到  蕾妮  讲
Yeah, Lanie. We're here. Go ahead.
赶紧来停尸房
Well, get your ass to the morgue.
我发现了令人不安的东西
I found something disturbing.
是啊  不安的事还挺多呢
Yeah, well, that seems to be going around.
是什么...
So, what is so --
那是血吗
Is that blood?
据蕾妮说不是的
Well, not according to Lanie.
那是什么
Then...what is it?
是墨水
Some kind of ink.
蕾妮把样本送去实验室了
Lanie sent samples to the lab,
但我们知道  从纹样看来
but one thing that we do know is, based on the writing,
加百列不可能是自己弄上去的
there's no way that Gabriel did this to himself.
那么是医院的什么人
So, then, someone at the hospital.
是啊  我打了电话  他们说
Yeah, I called, and they said
他今早逃出去时
that he didn't have any writing on him
身上还没有图案
when he escaped this morning.
罗马数字是《圣经》章节
The Roman numerals are bible verses,
文字都是拉丁语的
and the words are all in Latin.
"保护我  主  不受邪恶之手侵害"
"Protect me, O Lord, from the hands of the wicked."
是救赎祷文
It's a prayer for salvation.
听起来他在害怕  怕什么呢
Sounds like he was scared, but of what?
还不止这些谜团
The mysteries don't stop there.
我进行尸检的时候  我发现伤口
When I conducted the autopsy, I found that the wound
是什么爪子弄出来的
had been inflicted by some kind of talon or claw.
动物那样吗
Like an animal?
还有更怪的
It gets even weirder.
伤口内有种奇怪的物质
There was a strange substance inside the wound.
我猜猜  硫磺
Let me guess -- sulfur.
你怎么知道
Yeah, how'd you know?
各位  这还不明显吗
Guys, isn't it obvious?
拉丁祷文  爪子  硫磺  也就是
Latin prayers, a claw, sulfur -- also known...
硫磺石
as brimstone?
拜托  卡塞尔
Come on, Castle.
卡塞尔  你不是认为
Castle, you don't think that --
我就是
Oh, but I do.
我们都有心魔
We all have our demons.
但加百列的恶魔杀了他
But Gabriel was killed by his.
我怎么说的
What did I tell you?
一断电  就会发生坏事
I mean, as soon as the lights go out, bad things happen.
至少分局在用备用发电机
You know, at least the precinct is on a backup generator,
全城其他地方
'cause the rest of the city
都要间歇用电
is gonna have intermittent power.
今天会像地狱般难熬
Today's gonna be hell.
这话合适
Well, that's appropriate,
因为凶手很可能就来自那里
since that's the likely place our killer is from.
你说我们会不会需要特别武器
You know, do you think we're gonna need specialized equipment
来抓这个恶魔杀人犯  比如有驱魔性能的
to capture this demon murderer, something exorcism-esque?
这案子没什么超自然可言
There's nothing supernatural about this case.
被害人被沾有硫磺的爪子捅伤了
Our victim was stabbed with a brimstone-covered claw,
也或许是被角戳了
or gored by a horn, perhaps.
除了恶魔还有什么能做到啊
Now, what but a demon could do that?
莱恩和埃斯波
Look, Ryan and Espo are
这就要把玩失踪的护工戴维·霍比带来
bringing in Dave Holmby, our rogue orderly,
他们肯定能问出
and I am sure that they are going to get
非常正常  有理有据的
a very sane and grounded explanation
他杀加百列·肖的理由
as to why he killed Gabriel Shaw.
寻求真相  你究竟得到启蒙
Seek the truth - and thou shalt be enlightened.
是《圣经》里的吗
Is that scripture?
是卡塞尔福音里的
From the book of Castle.
我去  那场暴风雨真是厉害
Hot damn, that was some storm!
可不是  简直不让人活
Seriously, fit for neither man nor beast.
真是难以想象
I can only imagine how hard it was
在这样的天气里追踪一个精神病人有多困难
to track down an escaped mental patient in the middle of it.
是啊  真是赶上福尔摩斯的
Yeah, that was some Sherlock-level
侦探水平了  戴维
detective work, Dave.
纽约警局如果能招到你这样的人就太幸运了
NYPD would be lucky to have someone like you.
知道我们该干什么吗
You know what we should do?
-给他张申请表  -好主意
- Give him an application. - Ooh, that's a good idea.
但有杀人的问题
Ahh, there's that whole murder issue.
是啊
Right.
如果你昨晚逮到肖之后
If only you wouldn't have killed Shaw last night
没杀了他多好
after you caught him.
我倒不是不理解你  他偷了你的钥匙卡嘛
Not that I don't sympathize. I mean, he stole your keycard.
-是啊  -你大概要被解雇了
- Yep. - You probably were gonna get fired.
等等  我跟肖分开时  他还有气呢
Wait a minute. When I left Shaw, he was still alive.
那么你承认他跑了之后还见过他了
Oh, so you admit to seeing him after he escaped?
是的
Yeah.
他以前老提87街上的一家教堂
Look, he used to talk about this church on 87th street.
所以我去了那儿  他正往外走
So I went up there. There he was, walking out.
我抓住了他  想把他拖上我的车  但
I grabbed him, I tried to drag him into my car, but...
怎么了
But what?
他知道我
He knew that I was...
偷病人的药
liberating meds from patients
然后上街头转卖
and selling them on the street.
我猜猜
Let me guess.
他说如果你带他回去
He told you that if you took him back,
他就出卖你
he was gonna rat you out.
他是那么说还好了
I wish he said that.
他说无论如何都会把事说出去
He promised he was gonna out me no matter what.
等等  听上去
Wait a minute, that sounds like
你更有捅他的动机了
even more of a motive to stab the guy.
我发誓  我放他走了
I swear, I let him go.
他昨天4:30时还活着
He was alive at 4:30 yesterday,
那是我最后一次见到他
and that was the last time that I saw him.
你为什么没回皮科莫
So, why didn't you go back to Peakmore?
你为什么躲在你女友公寓里
Why were you hiding out at your girlfriend's apartment?
我没躲
I wasn't hiding.
我以为肖迟早要被抓到
I figured Shaw was gonna get caught sooner or later,
那么我无论如何也会丢了工作
which meant that I was out of a job no matter what.
所以我心想  算了
So I said screw it.
不如干脆给自己放假吧
Might as well take the rest of the night off and,
陪陪我女朋友
you know, spend some time with my girl.
就算这是真的
All right, let's pretend that that's true.
为什么现在  他都被关了20年了
Why now? After 20 years of confinement,
肖为什么突然决定越狱
why would Shaw decide to break out?
我只知道  这几周来
All I know is in the past few weeks,
他一直很激动
he was really amped up.
为什么  他出什么事了吗
Why? Something happen to him?
不是什么事  是什么人  有个探视者
Not something, someone -- a visitor.
谁
Who?
我不知道
I don't know.
但不管那人是谁  都让肖很激动
But whoever it was really set Shaw off.
他原本就很不稳定
I mean, he was already disturbed,
但那人来过之后  他情况更糟了
but after this guy came by, he got even worse.
我调出了肖20年前的
So, I pulled the police file and court records
警方案卷和法庭记录
for Shaw's prosecution 20 years ago,
据这里写  肖对克朗家的袭击
and according to this, Shaw's attack on the Crowne family
绝不是临时起意
was anything but random.
他当时是一名
He was working as a consultant
私家侦探诺亚·克雷默的顾问
for a P.I. named Noah Kramer.
什么样的顾问
What kind of consultant?
精神顾问
Spiritual.
克雷默受雇调查克朗一家
Kramer had been hired to investigate the Crowne family.
等等  一个私家侦探为什么要雇精神顾问
Wait. Why would a P.I. hire a spiritual consultant
协助调查一个亿万富翁慈善家
to help investigate a billionaire philanthropist?
怎么了
What? What is it?
我知道肖为什么来这间办公室了
I know why Shaw came to this office.
20年前  这里是诺亚·克雷默的办公室
20 years ago, this was Noah Kramer's office.
更新案件板了  那么一定是
Ooh, updating the murder board must mean
-霍比的不在场证明证实了  -是啊
- Holmby's alibi checked out? - That it did.
-太棒了  -不是吧
- Yes! - Really?
拜托  我就是很高兴结束了护工理论
Come on. I'm just excited to get off the whole orderly thing
踏上了寻找真正凶手的路程
and on to the trail of the true killer,
很可能是条通往地狱的路
which is most likely a road paved to hell,
因为我们都知道
because we all know
恶魔都是那里来的
that's where demons come from.
我一定会把肖的探视者
Well, I will be sure to cross reference
跟坠落天使名单做对比的  好吗
Shaw's visitor against the list of fallen angels, okay?
埃斯波西托拿到探视名单了吗
Has Esposito gotten the visitor logs yet?
他在办  但由于断电
Well, he's trying, but the power outage
什么事都很慢
is slowing everything down.
有什么问题吗
Something wrong?
看啊
Look at that.
似乎是镜头光晕  怎么了
Yeah, it looks just like a lens flair. Why?
-又出现了  -好奇怪
- There it is again. - Weird.
那不是
That's not...
爸爸  海莉和我做了调查  20年前
Dad, Hayley and I did some digging, and 20 years ago,
加百列·肖是一名私家侦探
Gabriel Shaw worked as a consultant
诺亚·克雷默的顾问  他就在你的办公室工作
for a P.I. named Noah Kramer who worked out of your office.
或许肖拿着斧子过去
It's possible that Shaw came there with the ax
是去找克雷默了
looking for Kramer.
这个理论不错  但克雷默早死了
Well, it's a nice theory, but Kramer's long dead.
肖被送入皮科莫
He was killed in an accident
一年半后他死于事故
a year and a half after Shaw was committed to Peakmore.
什么样的事故
What kind of an accident?
他被从一建筑工地坠落的管子刺穿了
He was impaled by a pipe that fell at a construction site.
好吧  好可怕
Okay. That's horrible.
但是  肖还是有可能因为头脑不清楚
But still, it's possible that Shaw was delusional enough
而以为克雷默还活着
to believe that Kramer was still alive.
或许吧  克雷默的妻子孩子
Maybe. You know, Kramer's wife and kid
还住在城里
still live in the city.
或许他们知道肖的动机
Perhaps they can shed some light on Shaw's motives.
告诉我他们的地址
Give me an address for them.
写下来
Write this down.
等等  我去拿支笔
Hang on, let me get a pen.
加百列·肖死了
Gabriel Shaw is dead?
我们昨天才见到他
We just saw him yesterday.
在哪
Where?
他来了我们家
Well, he came by the house.
他说皮科莫释放了他
He said he was released from Peakmore.
他有什么事
What did he want?
他想找20年前留给我父亲的东西
He was looking for stuff he left with my dad 20 years ago.
什么样的东西
What kind of stuff?
我不知道  我没问  我们
I don't know. I didn't ask. We --
我们不想跟他扯上关系
We didn't want anything to do with him.
他毁了我爸的生活
He ruined my dad's life.
马歇尔当时还太小  不记得
Marshall's too young to remember,
但他知道
but he's well aware
加百列·肖是如何毁了我们家
of how Gabriel Shaw ruined our family.
肖袭击了克朗一家后
After Shaw attacked the Crownes,
我丈夫的名誉尽毁
my husband's reputation was destroyed.
诺亚很震惊他结交的朋友
Noah was shocked to think that a man he befriended
居然暗藏如此邪恶
could've hidden such...evil.
诺亚觉得他们的合作
Noah thought the work they had done together
是个错误  需要掩埋起来
was a mistake and thought it needed to be buried.
你们有肖的东西吗
So, do you have anything of Shaw's?
没有  我丈夫死后
Oh, no. No, after my husband died,
我实在不忍进入他的办公室
I just couldn't bear going into his office,
于是我雇了家公司把家具都卖掉了
so I-I hired a company to sell off the furniture
然后把其他东西都丢掉了
and just dump the rest.
肖走之前我都告诉他了
I told Shaw all of this before he left.
那是几点
What time was that?
大概5点
Around 5:00.
据他碰到凶手还差3.5小时
That's still 3.5 hours before he met his murderer.
他有提到他接下来要去哪吗
Did he mention anything about where he was going next?
没有  但他走之前说了句拉丁语
No, but he said something in Latin before he walked away.
你还记得是什么吗  或许很重要
Do you remember what that was? It could be very important.
终结...我不知道
Finis omnium... I don't know.
即将到来
Nunc est.
终结即将到来
Finis omnium nunc est.
The end is upon us.
我知道肖昨晚为什么挥着斧子闯进来了
I know why Shaw came here wielding an ax last night.
罪孽地杀死
To commit unholy murder
两名出众得不可思议的女性吗
on two unbelievably exceptional women?
接近  但不对
Close, but no.
他是想进入那里
He was trying to get in there.
保险箱吗
The safe?
我租下办公室时  这里都被糊上了
This was all drywalled over when I rented the office.
我翻修时  承包商才发现了它
The contractors found it when I was doing the renovations.
房东以为已经拆掉了
The landlord thought it had been removed,
显然诺亚·克雷默死前筑墙把它封上了
but clearly Noah Kramer walled it up before he died,
意图埋葬他和肖在一同调查的东西
intent on burying whatever he and Shaw were working on.
所以肖才拿了把斧子
That's why Shaw grabbed the ax --
是想打开保险箱
to try and break into the safe.
-里面有什么  -我不知道
- So, what's inside? - I don't know.
等等  你从未打开过
Wait a minute. You've never opened --
为什么不啊
Why the hell not?
薛定谔的猫
Schrodinger's cat.
天呐  这又是他的
Oh, God. Is this another one of his --
这可好
Great!
不不  听我说
No, no. It's -- look.
如果我打开了它  我就注定要失望
If I opened it, I was bound to be disappointed
不管里面是有什么
with whatever was inside.
如果我不打开它
If I never opened it,
那么我想象的任何东西都可能在里面
literally anything I imagine could be in there.
所以你选择了幻想而非现实吗
So, you chose fantasy over reality?
当然
Well, duh.
但我们现在要打开它了  是吧
But we're going to open it now, right?
当然了
Well, duh.
如果有个被恶魔杀死的
When an ax-wielding psychopath
挥斧疯子想打开它  显然
is killed by a demon trying to get inside, clearly,
里面的东西绝对值得一看
whatever's in there is worth seeing.
如果
If only...
我认识会开保险箱的人就好了
I knew someone who could crack a safe?
是杰斐逊钛500保险箱
It's a Jefferson Titanium 500 vault.
什么意思
Meaning?
我需要28分钟和一杯巧克力奶昔
I need 28 minutes and a chocolate milkshake.
你开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
-巧克力奶昔  -没问题
- Chocolate milkshake. - Chocolate milkshake.
这就去
Chocolate milkshake.
-警监  -怎么
- Captain. - Yeah?
据皮科莫的探视记录
According to Peakmore's visitor's logs,
去探视肖的人叫丹尼斯·沃姆沃德
the person who came to see Shaw was named Dennis Wormwood.
很好  找到他了吗
Oh, good. Any luck finding him?
没有  这是个假名
No, because it's a fake name.
好吧  皮科莫肯定有监控
Okay, well, Peakmore must have security videos,
调出监控  看能否确认他身份
so pull the feed, see if you can ID him.
我调了
I did.
看看
Check this out.
好奇怪
Oh, that's strange.
该说恐怖
Creepy is more like it.
你觉得卡塞尔会不会是对的
So, do you think Castle's right --
不不不  不许你火上浇油
No, no, no, no. Don't even add fuel to that fire.
那个报了假名的人  肯定为了保密那次探视
Whoever gave the fake name must've sabotaged the videos
而破坏了监控录像
in order to keep that visit a secret,
因此他更可能是凶手了
which makes him look even more like our killer.
好吧  我会继续查的
All right, I'll keep digging.
这是不是...太吵了  我去...
Is this -- this is -- this is loud. I'm gonna...
好了
Got it.
好了  这是你最后
Okay, it's your last chance
发挥想象的机会了
to let your imagination run wild.
-我不用再想了  -或许我们不该打开
- I'm good. - Eh, maybe we shouldn't.
考虑到魔鬼落跑精神病人什么的
Given the whole Satanic, escaped-mental-patient angle?
阿丽克西斯  我们不能让恐惧控制我们的行为
Alexis, we can't let fear control our actions.
想重新考虑吗
Care to rethink that?
进去了
Here we go.
都是什么啊
What is it all?
看起来是调查
Looks like research.
调查什么
Into what?
世界末日
The end of days.
据这上面讲  就将发生在两天后
Which, according to this, is two days from now.
天呐  我讨厌疯狂墙
Man, I hate walls of crazy.
如果不是疯言疯语呢
What if it's not crazy?
肖认为天启将于两天后开始
Shaw believed the apocalypse starts in two days.
那肖为什么要再进来这里
Then why did Shaw want to get back inside of here?
他想要什么
What was he after?
是啊  好问题
Yeah. It's a good question.
想想看  这些东西一直就在我们身旁
It's insane to think that this has all been sitting
太疯狂了
right next to us all this time.
简直变态
It's twisted.
看来他们在跟踪这个男孩  维科特·克朗
Looks like they were following this boy, Victor Crowne.
等等  克朗  那就是20年前
Wait, Crowne. That was the family
肖企图谋害的一家
that Shaw tried to murder 20 years ago.
是啊  我查了他们
Yeah, I looked into them.
父母是沃伦和爱丽丝·克朗
Warren and Alice Crowne were the parents.
他们有个九岁儿子维科特
They had a nine-year-old boy named Victor.
更糟的是  肖的袭击没有杀死他们
What's worse, after surviving Shaw's attacks,
之后却在滑雪时遭遇诡异雪崩而死
they were killed in a freak skiing avalanche
维科特成了孤儿
and Victor became an orphan.
可怜的孩子
Poor kid.
是  也不是  他们是亿万富翁
Well, yes and no. They were billionaires.
维科特将继承全部财产
Victor stood to inherit the entire fortune.
开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
各位  你们看出来了吧
Guys, tell me you're seeing this.
一名身处世界末日阴谋中央
A targeted orphan standing to inherit an empire
将继承大笔财产  被人盯上的孤儿
in the center of a religious Armageddon plot?
拜托
Hello!
这是《凶兆》
It's "The Omen"!
肖认定维科特·克朗是反基督者
Shaw believed that Victor Crowne was the Antichrist.
是...你是指
The A-- as in...
就是魔鬼的化身
As in the personification of the devil.
是的  亲爱的  没错
Yes, dear. Yes. It --
所以肖才会袭击克朗夫妇
That's why Shaw went after the Crownes.
他其实是想杀他们儿子
He was going after their son.
但那是一部电影
Except that was a film.
别告诉我
Please don't tell me
你在谷歌反基督者
you are Googling the Antichrist right now.
我在调查维科特·克朗
I'm looking into Victor Crowne.
他还住在纽约
He still lives here in New York.
如果肖认为维科特真是魔鬼
If Shaw believed that Victor was some sort of devil,
或许那是他从精神病院逃出来的原因
maybe that's why he escaped from that institution --
好去完成任务
so that he could finish his mission.
据文章说  两天后
According to this article, in two days,
维科特·克朗就将满30岁  可以完全控制
Victor Crowne turns 30 and will gain full control
他父母的商业帝国
over his parents' empire.
这就对了
That's it.
耶稣是30岁开始布道
Jesus began his ministry when he was 30.
很多人认为反基督者
Many people believe that the Antichrist
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
也将在同样的年龄开始统治地球
will begin his reign on Earth at the same age.
一旦他升天
And that once his ascension has started,
就无法阻止他了
it cannot be stopped.
各位  如果维科特·克朗真是反基督者
Guys, what if Victor Crowne is the Antichrist
肖并没疯呢
and Shaw isn't crazy?
不  里克  他绝对是疯子
No, Rick. He was very crazy.
记得吗  他想杀个孩子
Remember -- he tried to kill a child.
我们还没把肖逃跑后的
You know, we still haven't accounted for
时间线都查清
all of Shaw's time after he escaped.
如果他仍然执念于杀死维科特
If he's still obsessed with killing Victor,
那昨晚他就很有可能是冲着杀人去的
there's a chance he took a run at him last night.
可维科特已经是成年人  有能力保护自己
Except Victor is a full-grown man now, able to defend himself.
如果维科特在自卫过程中刺伤了肖
And if Victor stabbed Shaw in self-defense,
他也许因为害怕而不敢站出来
he might be too afraid to come forward.
我们得和这个人谈谈
We need to talk to this guy.
拜托  大半个城市都断电了
Come on. Half the city is blacked out,
这里居然还亮的像棵圣诞树
but this place is lit up like a Christmas tree?
-也许是用发电机发的电呢  -没错
- The lights probably run on generators. - Sure.
用地狱之火驱动的热能发电机
Thermoelectric generator fueled by the flames of Hell.
看看这个  伙计们  看这个
Check this out, you guys. Look at this.
身家亿万的企业家一心要用他的
Billionaire entrepreneur hell-bent on "Saving the world"
净化水项目"拯救世界"  那肯定没错了
with his water reclamation project? I'm sure.
卡塞尔  众所周知  维科特·克朗
Castle, by all accounts, Victor Crowne has helped
通过提供干净的饮用水
millions of impoverished people
帮助了很多贫困的人
by providing them with clean drinking water.
或者是用它来感染我们
Or is he infecting us with it?
先生们  请跟我这边走
Gentlemen, follow me this way, please.
你从保险箱里偷了这个来保护你自己
You stole this from the safe to protect yourself?!
卡塞尔
Castle!
怎么了  你们有枪保护
What?! You guys have guns.
纽约警局
The NYPD.
还有理查德·卡塞尔本人
And Richard Castle in the flesh.
我是你们所有人的粉丝
I'm fans of you all.
你身上有静电
Yikes! You got a shock.
这可真让人讨厌  不是吗
Don't you hate when that happens?
有什么可以让我为诸位效劳呢
So, how can I help you fine gentlemen?
克朗先生  我们想问几个关于这个人的问题
Mr. Crowne, we just have some questions about this man.
看来你认出他是谁了
I take it you recognize him.
加百列·肖  永生难忘
Gabriel Shaw. Hard face to forget.
你最近见过他吗
Have you seen him recently?
你们到底想说什么
Okay, what's this all about?
肖死了
Shaw is dead.
他昨天下午从皮科莫逃走
He escaped from Peakmore yesterday afternoon
之后在夜里被杀害
and was killed later that evening.
你看起来很高兴
You seem pleased.
这人袭击了我的家人  卡塞尔先生
The man attacked my family, Mr. Castle.
别指望我为他的死掉一滴眼泪
Don't expect me to shed a tear over his demise.
20年了  这张脸让我不得安宁
20 years, this face has haunted me.
为什么这样
How's that?
受袭后  我父母带我离开了这座城市
Days after his attack, my parents and I left the city.
我的父母死于途中一场诡异的事故
My parents perished in a freak accident on that trip.
你认为他们的死是肖的错
You blame Shaw for their deaths.
他触发了连锁反应
He set those events in motion.
那个人永久地诅咒了我的人生
That man forever cursed my life.
但我把我的痛苦化作福祉
But I've turned my pain into a blessing.
把所有的负能量
Channeled all that negative energy
投入到一个造福人类的计划
into a plan for something good -- a better world.
我的净化水项目
My clean-water initiative.
就在这几天  我们将启动
We're launching a global network of offices
这个全球项目计划
in just a couple of days.
在你30岁生日的时候
On your 30th birthday.
恰巧  是的
As it so happens, yes.
尽管我不想  克朗先生
Well, I hate to have to ask you this, Mr. Crowne,
但我还是要问昨天晚上你在哪里
but where were you last night?
这里  工作
Here. Working.
罗林斯可以为你们提供监控录像
Rollins can provide you with surveillance tapes
如果你们想核实的话
if you'd like to verify that.
说完了
We're done here.
先生们
Gentlemen.
那是什么
What is that --
什么东西闻起来像是
Something smells like --
硫磺
Sulfur.
昨天我们在展示中出了点意外
We had an accident during a demonstration yesterday.
我还在设法解决
I'm still working out the kinks.
警探们
Detectives.
我把我们的监控录像刻录了备份
I burned those copies of our surveillance tapes.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢了  罗林斯
Thanks, Rollins.
这是过去48小时内每个楼层的录像
Every floor for the last 48 hours.
谢了  罗林斯  非常感谢
Thanks, Rollins. Really appreciate it.
不客气
You're welcome.
-卡塞尔  -我的妈呀
- Castle? - Geez!
你怎么了
What's with you?
我  我被死亡标记了
I-I'm -- I'm marked for death.
什么
What?
我被死亡标记了
I'm marked for death.
伙计  你可别再看那些恐怖片了
Bro, you have to stop watching these horror films.
跟罪案现场照片里
That same slash of light
出现的光线一模一样
appeared in the crime-scene photos, okay?
位置也一样  就在我的脖子上
In the exact same place -- right across my neck.
现在视频里又出现了
Now it's showing up again in the video feed?
那是实时监控  不可能被动手脚
That's live feed! That cannot be manipulated!
卡塞尔  所有关于凶兆和反基督者...
Castle, all this stuff about omens and the Antichrist --
你被死亡标记等等
You being marked for death...
都是你胡思乱想的
It's all in your head.
-伙计们  -小心
- Guys -- - Look out!
现在又怎么说呢
You were saying?!
碰巧绳子磨损严重而已
It was a frayed cable.
是是  我同意  如果你说的破绳子是指撒旦的话
Yes. Yes, I agree. If by frayed cable, you mean Satan.
听着  卡塞尔  别误会
Look, Castle, don't take this the wrong way,
你听起来有点发疯
but you're starting to sound crazy.
不是你平日里的那种疯  而是变本加厉的疯
And not your usual crazy, I mean, next-level nutter.
贝克特  听我说
Beckett, listen to me.
我看着维科特·克朗冷漠无情的眼睛
I looked into the cold, soulless eyes of Victor Crowne,
告诉你我看到了什么...
and let me tell you what I saw --
邪恶
Evil.
我看了维科特·克朗的
Well, I looked into the surveillance tapes
大楼监控录像
from Victor Crowne's building,
告诉你我看到了什么
and let me tell you what I saw --
维科特·克朗整晚都在工作
Victor Crowne working all night.
他根本没有离开过大楼  卡塞尔
He never left the building, Castle.
他不是我们的凶手
He's not our killer.
他不受地球上的规则约束  贝克特
He's not gonna be bound by earthly laws, Beckett.
恶魔的基础常识
That's Demon 101.
警监
Yo, Cap.
我们还是没弄清楚案发期间
We're still not having any luck figuring out where Shaw was
肖到底在哪里
during that time-of-death window.
一定有人见过他
Well, someone must've seen him,
-不如让警员再排查一遍吧  -好的
- so why don't we get unis to re-canvass? - All right.
我刚刚接到蕾妮的电话
Yo, I just got a call from Lanie.
你们还记得印在受害者尸体上的
Uh, do you remember the biblical verses
圣经章节吗
painted all over our Vic's body?
实验室做了分析  而结果非常奇怪
Well, the lab ran an analysis, and the results are...odd.
颜料是一种由橄榄油
It's a paste made from a mixture
肉桂  桂皮  香茅  没药混合而成
of olive oil, cassia, cinnamon, cymbopogon, and myrrh.
香茅和没药吗  我好像在哪见过
Cymbopogon and myrrh? I've seen this somewhere before.
我发誓
I swear it.
-跟上  -好吧
- Go. - All right.
大家好
Hey, guys.
爸爸
Hey, Dad.
你简直无法相信我们在这找到了什么
You wouldn't believe some of the stuff we're finding in here.
你有找到过一份食谱吗
Did you find a recipe?
什么的食谱  反基督者饼干吗
For what? Antichrist cookies?
不  当然不是
No, of course not.
但实际上  我也不知道
But, actually, I don't even know.
我只知道我在这看到过一封有写食谱的信
All I know is I saw a letter in here that had a recipe on it
里面提到了橄榄油  肉桂  桂皮  香茅和没药
with olive oil, cassia, cinnamon, cymbopogon, and myrrh.
等等  怎么听起来这么耳熟呢
Wait, wait, wait a minute. Why does that sound so familiar?
等等  等一下
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
对  在这
Yeah, here it is.
是一个叫卡尔·冯·埃克兰的人写给加百列·肖的
It's addressed to Gabriel Shaw from a Karl Von Eckland.
这封信里面一直在说一种膏油
Now the letter goes on and on and on about anointing oil.
是古时候用来准备
It was used in ancient times to prepare the righteous
与恶魔战斗的东西
for battle against demons,
它的原材料包含了香茅和没药
and the ingredients include cymbopogon and myrrh.
来听一下这部分
Okay, now listen to this part.
"轮到你听从召唤
"Find me when it's your turn to answer the call.
我会帮你准备抵抗魔鬼的战斗"
I will prepare you - for your battle against evil."
写这个的人是谁来着
And who's the guy who wrote that?
卡尔·冯·埃克兰
Karl Von Eckland.
我们确实得跟这人谈谈
We really need to talk to this guy.
但他已经死了
Well, um, he's dead.
除非你在这找个通灵板
So, unless you have a Ouija board somewhere around here,
这难度恐怕有点大
it might be a bit of a challenge.
他怎么死的
How did he die?
貌似是1996年12月13日心脏病突发
Looks like he had a fatal heart attack on December 13, 1996.
就是写完这封信的一个月之后
That is just one month after this letter was written.
也是加百列·肖被送到皮科莫的一周后
And a week after Gabriel Shaw was sent to Peakmore.
等等  如果肖被关在精神病院
Wait a minute. If Shaw was institutionalized,
很有可能他不知道卡尔·冯·埃克兰死了
it's possible he didn't know Karl Von Eckland was dead.
也就是说他逃出来以后
Which means after he broke out,
他可能会去冯·埃克兰的公寓里
he probably went to Von Eckland's apartment to get prepared
为他要面对的恶魔之战做准备
for his supposed demonic battle.
莱恩  现在住在冯·埃克兰公寓里的是谁
Ryan, who lives in Von Eckland's apartment now?
他的儿子奥斯卡
His son, Oscar.
似乎他父亲死后他就搬进去了
Looks like he moved in after his father died.
地方不错
Nice place.
真是不拘一格
It's very, uh... eclectic.
是  也诡异得要命
Yeah, it's creepy as all hell,
但都是我爸爸的旧物
but it's my dad's old stuff.
实在不忍心把这些丢掉
Never had the heart to get rid of any of it.
你没有继承你父亲的宗教事业吗
So, you didn't follow in your father's religious footsteps?
当然没有
Hell, no.
都是迷信罢了
It's all mumbo jumbo.
二十块吗
20 bucks?
总要混口饭吃不是吗
Hey, a man's got to eat, right?
所以我就在这赚点小钱
So, I make a little money on the side.
就把这些神圣的废物卖给那些傻子
You know, selling blessed crap to suckers.
有祝福的蜡烛  神圣的十字架
Yeah, blessed candles, blessed crosses.
你对祝福手链感兴趣吗
Can I interest you in a blessed bracelet?
没有  但我们对这个人有兴趣
No, but, uh, we are interested in this man.
他昨晚来了这吗
Was he here last night?
对  六点左右
Yeah. Around 6:00.
叫加百列什么的吗
Gabriel something?
来找我爸
Was looking for my old man.
他想让你父亲给他抹点神油
He wanted your father to anoint him
为一场圣战做准备
with the oil for spiritual battle.
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
你给他抹神油了吗  奥斯卡
Did you anoint him, Oscar?
五十块  当然抹了
For 50 bucks, hell yeah, I did.
怎么了  他很坚持想要
What? He was desperate,
于是我就找了本我爸的旧书
so I grabbed one of Pop's old books,
然后就做了一点神油出来
and I whipped up a batch of the anointing oil,
我还在他身上写了点圣经章节
and I, uh, wrote some bible verses on him.
这让他平静了很多
It gave him great peace.
但这平静没持续多久  那人已经死了
Well, that peace didn't last. The man's dead.
真的吗  他怎么了
Really? What happened to him?
他被撒旦的子嗣杀死了
He was murdered... by the spawn of Satan.
-他是说真的吗  -很认真
- Is he serious? - Very.
奥斯卡  加百列·肖有没有告诉你
So, Oscar, did Gabriel Shaw
他要去见什么人
tell you whether he was meeting anyone?
他有说他要去哪吗
Did he say where he was going?
没有  他谢了我然后就走了
No, just thanked me and left.
-他几点走的  -七点半过一点
- What time did he leave? - A little after 7:30.
就是肖被刺前三十分钟
That's 30 minutes before Shaw was stabbed.
伙计们  我们很接近了
Guys, we're getting close.
所以有好消息也有坏消息
Okay, so good and bad news.
好消息就是我们找到了
The good news is we found surveillance footage
肖在奥斯卡家附近的监控录像
of Shaw in Oscar's neighborhood
这样我们就能找到
and we were able to track him back
他被刺的位置是哪
to the location where he was stabbed.
你们有加百列·肖被害的录像吗
You have video of Gabriel Shaw's murder?
算是有吧
Well, yeah. Uh, sort of.
所以就有坏消息了是吧
This is where the bad news comes in.
由于那场雷暴雨
It appears that due to the thunderstorm,
所有的监控摄像都有点失灵了
none of the cameras are functioning properly.
什么意思
What does that mean?
这个  这有点怪
It -- Uh...It's just gonna be sort of...odd.
一般的奇怪吗  还是魔鬼般诡异那种怪
Like odd odd? Or work of the Devil odd?
不  就一般的奇怪  卡塞尔  好吗
No, just odd odd, Castle, all right?
-放吧  -好的
- Go ahead. - Okay.
那就是恶魔
That...is a demon.
朋友们  你们做到了
You guys, you did it.
你们手上有加百列·肖
You have video of Gabriel Shaw
被不属于这世上的东西杀害的录像
killed by something not of this world.
行了  卡塞尔  别激动
All right, Castle. Easy.
听着大家伙  我知道是有点晚
Look, guys, I-I know it's late,
但我要你们去一趟那个码头
but I need you to go down to that loading dock
看能不能找到什么线索  拜托了
and see what you can find, please.
好
Yeah.
辛苦了
Thank you.
我去收拾一下
I'm gonna go pack up.
卡塞尔
And, um...Castle?
只是故障而已
It's just a glitch.
"反基督者出现
"And the beast shall rise
示以精明非凡之象
and appear as astute and miraculous --
领袖借由繁荣及平和之态
the leader who comes into power
上台掌权
on a platform of prosperity and peace."
或者简而言之
Or, in a nutshell,
维科特·克朗
Victor Crowne.
我的妈呀
Geez!
吓到你啦
Gotcha.
一点都不好玩  贝克特
Not funny, Beckett!
我被神秘力量盯上了
I am being targeted by dark forces.
我是认真的  我能感觉到
I'm serious. I can feel it.
好吧  但你明天再感觉行不行
Okay, fine. Can you just feel it in the morning?
已经很晚了  去睡吧
'Cause it's late. Let's go to bed.
行  我一会儿就去
Yeah, just give me a few minutes.
好吧
All right.
-吓  -我的妈呀
- Boo! - Geez!
你太好唬啦
You're so easy!
天使匕首
The Angel Dagger.
在哪见过来着
Where have I seen --
贝克特
Hey, Beckett.
你在哪
Hey, where are you?
我在办公室
I'm at the office.
我知道肖为什么要闯进来了
I figured out why Shaw broke in here.
-是吗  -对
- Really? - Yeah.
他是来找一把兵器的
He was looking for a weapon.
能杀死反基督者的唯一兵器
It's the only thing that can kill the Antichrist.
叫天使匕首
It's called the Angel Dagger.
卡塞尔  别闹了
Castle, would you please just --
贝克特  我没开玩笑
Beckett, I am serious.
我在网上找到了相关信息  而且匕首就在这
I-I found references to it on the Internet, and it was here.
一直放在保险箱里
It's been in the safe the whole time.
刀身就藏在...
I-It's a blade that was hidden in a --
-谁在那  -谁在那
- Who's there? - Who's where?
喂  卡塞尔
Hello? Castle --
他来了
He's here.
谁
Who?
卡塞尔
Castle?
喂
Hello?
我看到他的眼睛了  他是恶魔
I saw his eyes. It was a demon.
或者只是个戴了夜视镜的人
Or someone with night-vision goggles.
贝克特  你还要多少证据
Beckett, how much proof do you need
才能相信
before you finally accept the fact
你丈夫已经被标记了死亡
that your husband has been marked for death!
如果你真的被标记了死亡
Okay, if you were marked for death,
那恶魔早就杀了你
then the demon would've killed you.
相反  那个人偷袭敲晕你
Instead, you were knocked out by a very human attacker
然后抢走你说的那个什么鬼匕首
who managed to run off with your...w-whatever dagger.
-天使匕首  -是天使匕首
- Angel Dagger! - Angel -- Angel Dagger.
天使匕首  只有恶魔才会想得到的东西
Angel Dagger. It's something only a demon would want.
如果是真的  那为什么恶魔要洗劫你的保险箱
Look, if that's true, then why did the demon ransack your safe?
当然是为了寻找其他有超自然能力的宝贝
Hello? To look for other items with supernatural abilities.
-难道...  -卡塞尔
- Is it--  - Hey, Castle.
你没事吧  哥们
How you doing, buddy?
我和魔鬼对视了
Well, boys, I looked into the eyes of the devil,
就是这样
so there's that.
他是不是脑震荡了
Did they check him for a concussion?
没  他只是有点受惊了
Uh, no. He's fine. He's just a little shaken.
你们调查出什么了吗
You guys got anything on the canvass?
有个保安在
Yeah, a bouncer who was working at a club
肖被刺现场对面的一家俱乐部上班
across the alley from where Shaw's stabbing took place
他看到了一辆银色探险者从那开出
saw a gray Explorer tear ass out of there.
有车牌号吗
All right, did you get the plates?
没有  但我们不需要
Nope, and we don't need them.
因为这宗案件里只有一个人
Turns out there's only one person in this case
有银色探险者这款车
who has a gray Explorer.
我是有  但那款车很多人开
Oh, yeah? Well, a lot of people have that kind of SUV.
没错  但可没那么多人
Yes, but not a lot of people
车库里藏有凶器
have the murder weapon in their garage.
我们搜查了你家
See, we got a search warrant for your place,
找到了你的园林钳
and, uh, we found your garden claw.
这解释了为什么肖尸体上有爪状伤痕
So, that explains the claw-shaped wound on Shaw's body.
看吧  卡塞尔
See, Castle?
根本没有恶魔
No demon.
那为什么肖尸体上
Yeah, then, uh, why was there sulfur,
会有硫磺呢
i.e. Brimstone, found in Shaw's body.
我们实验室对凶器作了检验
Our labs did an analysis of the murder weapon,
上面不仅有肖的血迹
and not only did they find traces of Shaw's blood on it,
还有残存的含硫园艺肥分子
but they also found particles of sulfuric gardening fertilizer,
刚好能与死者伤口上的硫磺相匹配
which matches the sulfur we found in the wound.
有什么要补充吗
Anything else?
我只是想跟他讲道理
I was just trying to talk some sense into him,
但肖却不停地念叨他
but Shaw just started rambling
消除恶魔的使命
about his mission to vanquish evil.
他才是真正的恶魔
He was the true evil.
如果你只是想和他讲道理
If all you wanted to do was talk,
那为什么要带凶器去
then why did you bring the murder weapon?
我在车里放了花店要用的工具
I keep tools for my flower shop in my SUV.
我也不知道怎么回事  他一直没完没了
And, I don't know, he just started going on and on,
然后我就抓起了钳子
and I grabbed the claw.
二十年前  那家伙毁了我的家庭
20 years ago, that man ruined my family,
我不能让他再毁一次
and I couldn't let him do it all over again to us.
克雷默太太  你为什么昨晚要闯入
Mrs. Kramer, why did you break into
你丈夫以前的办公室
your husband's old office last night?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
没必要再隐瞒了
There's no reason to lie now.
我们知道是你拿了天使匕首
We know you took the Angel Dagger.
我整晚都和我儿子在一块
I was home all night with my son.
如果袭击我的不是她  那到底是谁呢
If she wasn't the one who attacked me, who the hell did?
有什么线索能找到卡塞尔的恶魔袭击者吗
Yo, any evidence to help identify Castle's demonic assailant?
没有  不过  里克  袭击你的人
No, but, Rick, whoever attacked you
还拿走了关于克朗家族的所有档案
also took all of the files on the Crowne family.
这个狡猾的魔鬼
That sneaky little devil.
是维科特·克朗干的
It's Victor Crowne. He did this.
你怎么知道
How do you figure?
很明显他是想拿走任何对他不利的东西
Well, clearly he's trying to take possession of any weapon
并且消除一切
that could be used against him and erase any and all evidence
能表明他撒旦之子身份的证据
of his true identity as the spawn of Satan.
我们已经查过维科特·克朗了
We already looked into Victor Crowne.
他整晚都待在一家俱乐部庆祝三十岁生日
He was out celebrating all night at a club for his 30th birthday.
那到底还有谁会这么不择手段呢
Okay, who else is gonna go to such lengths?
不知道  不过他落了个东西
Well, we don't know, but they left a souvenir.
这不是保险箱里原来的东西
This was not in the original inventory of the safe's contents.
这是奥斯卡·冯·埃克兰的手链
Yo, that's Oscar Von Eckland's bracelet.
为什么他会想要天使匕首
Why would he want the Angel Dagger?
因为他一直参与其中
Because he was in on it the whole time.
你们记得精神病院里
Do you remember the distorted image
肖的神秘访客的失真图像吗
of Shaw's mystery visitor at the psychiatric facility?
维克拉姆把它复原了
Well, Vikram was able to clean it up.
他说自己不相信宗教
He said he didn't believe in all this religious stuff.
他在说谎  你们都知道这说明什么
He lied, and you all know what that means.
说明他疯了吗
That he's insane.
不  不像肖  他的神志很清醒
No, unlike Shaw, he has all his faculties,
但是奥斯卡和他的先父一样是虔诚的信徒
but Oscar, like his father before him, is a true believer.
他要继承先父的未完事业
He's gonna pick up where his old man left off --
-完成使命  -杀死反基督者
- complete the mission. - Kill the Antichrist.
奥斯卡要刺杀维科特·克朗
Oscar's gonna assassinate Victor Crowne.
罗林斯  封锁大楼  确保维科特·克朗的安全
Hey, Rollins, lock down the building and secure Victor Crowne.
慢着  怎么了
Whoa, whoa, whoa. What's going on?
-你老板有生命危险  -你见过这个人吗
- Your boss is in danger. - Have you seen this man?
这是刚来的公证人  带着法律文件
That's the notary who just showed up with legal documents
让克朗先生签字
for Mr. Crowne to sign.
你放他进去见克朗先生了吗
Did you give him access to Mr. Crowne?
放了  但是有人陪同
Yes, but not without an escort.
马瑞拉  回话
Varella, come in.
马瑞拉  你在哪儿呢
Varella, what's your 20?
-他们去哪儿了  -地下室
- Where did they go? - Basement.
我们马上要进行大翻修
We're about to start a major renovation.
克朗独自去楼下现场视察了
Mr. Crowne's down there alone walking the site.
这样吧  分开行动
All right, let's split up.
-你俩走那边  我们走这边  -明白
- You two go that way, we'll go this way. - Got it.
-有人倒下了  -是啊
- Somebody's down. - Yeah.
他还活着
He's still alive.
卡塞尔  把他拖到楼上安全的地方去  行吗
All right, Castle, drag him upstairs to safety, all right?
-好  等等  让我去  -是啊
- Yeah. Wait -- me? - Yeah.
-我自己去  -是的
- By myself? - Yes!
好吧
Okay.
二位
Guys?
速速退去  邪恶的魔鬼  滚回地狱的最深处
Te expello, daemon vilis, in abyssum profundissimum Tartari!
奥斯卡  奥斯卡
Oscar! Oscar.
卡塞尔  救救我
Castle! Do something.
住手
Don't do it.
他是恶魔
He is the beast.
法外之徒
The lawless one.
地狱之子
The son of perdition.
罪恶之源
All bad things.
但是你记得《圣经》说过"不可杀人"吗
But thou shalt not kill, remember?
他不是人  所以这不算谋杀
He isn't human, so it's not murder.
祝你在法庭上这样辩解的时候好运吧
Good luck selling that in a court of law.
够了
Enough!
我必须阻止世界末日
I have to stop the end of days.
我对先父发过誓
I promised my father.
别动
No! Don't! No!
你做了什么
What have you done?!
如果我非得先杀你不可  那我也会杀了你
If I have to kill you first, I will!
奥斯卡  当心
Oscar, look out!
-卡塞尔  -卡塞尔  你在哪儿呢
- Castle! - Castle, where are you?!
我在这里
Over here!
-你没事吧  -没事  你呢
- You okay? - Yeah, you?
没事  我挺好的
Yeah. Good.
-你没事吧  -没事  我挺好的  你呢
- You okay? - Yeah, I'm still good. You?
我也没事
Yeah, I'm okay.
既然你们都没事  谁能给我松绑吗
Now that we know you're all okay, can someone untie me?
对啊  不好意思
Right. Sorry.
真走运  那些管子掉的真是时候  对吧
We're lucky those pipes fell when they did, huh?
是啊  走运
Yeah. Lucky.
谢谢你救了我
Thank you for saving me.
只想弄清楚  你真的不是反基督者  对吧
Just to be clear, you really aren't the Antichrist, right?
你可真幽默
Ahh, I love your sense of humor.
你救了我的命
You saved my life.
所以我欠你的
That means I owe you.
不管你需要什么
So, whatever you want,
只要开口就是你的  好吗
just ask. It's yours. Okay?
好的
Okay.
我刚才是不是真的
Did I just literally...
和魔鬼做了个交易
make a deal with the Devil?
奥斯卡被送去皮科莫
So, Oscar's on his way to Peakmore
做全面的精神评估了
for a full psych evaluation.
好吧  希望他们可以帮到他
Okay, well, let's hope they can help him.
这不大可能吧
I wouldn't hold my breath.
他们就没把肖管好
They didn't do so great with Shaw.
老大
Hey, boss.
你老公干吗呢
What's your husband doing?
卡塞尔  你简直是失控了
Castle, this is getting out of hand.
我身上还有死亡标记
I'm... still marked for death.
按说救了反基督者的命
Oh, well, you'd think that saving the Antichrist
真的能让你逃过一劫呢
would actually give you a pass.
你就笑话我吧  我要是死了你会想我的
You know, you mock, but you're gonna miss me when I'm gone.
你死不了
You're not going anywhere.
你怎么能确定
How can you be so sure?
把你的夹克脱下来
Take off your jacket.
我真心觉得现在不是
I really don't think this is the time --
把夹克脱下来
Take off your jacket.
好了  再自拍一张看看
Okay, now take another selfie.
怎么会
How...
你胸前口袋上的拉链
The zipper on your chest pocket.
它反光
It was catching the light, causing a flare.
我没有死亡标记
I'm not marked for death.
听你的口气还挺失望的
You sound disappointed there.
你开玩笑吗  我都激动死了
Are you kidding? I'm thrilled.
我们庆祝一下吧
Let's celebrate.
我们来玩裸体扭扭乐
Naked Twister.
其实  我有别的主意
Actually, I had something else in mind.
我们真该去我家看电影的
We really could've done movie night at my place.
不行  我们得摆脱对这里的心理阴影
No, no. We need to get rid of some of the bad vibes in here.
那么我们看什么  爱情喜剧片
So, what are we watching -- Rom-com?
动作喜剧片
Action-comedy?
惊悚片
Horror!
-你开玩笑吧  -没开玩笑
- You're kidding. - No.
拜托  我们刚从斧头底下逃过一劫
Oh, come on. We just survived the ax man.
《弗莱迪大战杰森》对我们来说就是发泄而已
A little Freddy-Jason action will be cathartic.
好吧  但是如果我晚上睡不着觉的话
All right, but if I can't sleep tonight,
明天早上我会揍你的
I'm kicking your ass in the morning.
做梦去吧
In your dreams.
海莉
Hayley?
撤
Run.
你真是个天才
That was genius.
现在可以玩裸体扭扭乐了吧
Now can we play naked Twister?